so I just finished watching the Google
internal document ie black me repa sewed
about the selfish ledger the idea being
that as we live our lives Google
collects information on us and then they
can tailor our decisions for what Google
decides is agreed or good Google's very
good really which is exactly what it
will always be it will be what makes the
most money for Google that's not what
they say in their internal document but
there's a point where the AI data
machine wants someone's weight so
knowing everything they know about them
they tailor make a scale and tell them
to buy it right they make it available
in the ads so that hopefully the person
buys it hopefully uses the smart device
and of course then they'll get their
weight instead of if it was truly
beneficial to get your weight just
asking you for it just asking hey I want
to stop by a cooperatively owned
Resource Centre for your health for
whatever and use all the smart devices
that can get all the metrics we need to
help you improve your health which is
why most of what they talk about my
confidence under a tree like this is
both amazing and horrific Google doing
it will always be horrific however if we
can do something like that if we can
make our data available to each other on
a case-by-case basis willing and
transparent so hey we need your weight
well why do you need my weight what for
the purpose of that because we want to
help tailor make a diet that will cure
your diabetes we want to help I don't
know
sit have safety devices for the city we
need to know people's average weight
whatever the actual reason is behind it
you can choose whether your and
beginning no one is gonna want to give
their data because we don't feel safe
and this exists but Google is always
gonna have to do it in the secret
they're gonna have to do it or they have
to like in the backend create a scale
and for and trick you into by unit so
that they get your weight instead of
what we can do together which is hey do
we need each other's weights well I
don't maybe want you to know my exact
weight
but I'm willing to have that in the
system for other people to be able to
use if my dad has washed and made safe
for the greater good and the more we
come up with those metrics together if
we were the ones in in our individual
group saying well we need to wait for
this for this thing one we're gonna have
people say well I'm not comfortable
giving my weight that's not that's not
okay and so well what would make you
feel safe giving your weight right is
there a way to actually get it from you
without tricking you into giving it what
is it you need to feel safe to feel okay
and then giving that to the person so
that we get all of the data that all of
the people that are like them won't give
unless those parameters are in place so
the selfish ledger is because it the
reason it's called the selfish lester
ledger is it's somewhat based on The
Selfish Gene theory and Lamarque and
genetics and even like Dawkins work on
the Selfish Gene even when I was reading
an undergrad it was like I love like
this concept like as a concept not an
actual fact because genes work on every
level or sorry evolution works on every
level it works on the gene level it
works on the population level you could
be the most selfish gene in the world if
you're not able to propagate your
species you've got no one to breed with
and no no way to and so the selfless
ledger the one that is the reason I'm
giving this data is for my benefit and
the benefit of the greater good and if
it's on blockchain if it's if it's um
triple ledger entry and available to
everyone in a way that's safe enough for
the user or you can't look up jubblies
weight and diet but you can see my
overall diet my overall up-and-down
weight I can see it my doctor can see it
if I want to share that information and
always have the user be in control and
having the conversations about what can
this be used for that it's the greater
benefit for me and the rest of the world
right now I get to decide this not
Google gets to decide it in a board
and then implement crazy ridiculous AI
that make that course is us and to
follow in a path they've somehow set out
and decided is the greater good
instead of like what do you need and how
can we get it to you
and what do we need and can we get it
from you and those things hopefully are
tied together well if you give us your
weight I'll give you this
we need your weight why well whatever
reason we've decided we need it we
decided we needed it and so people are
more likely to give it but nobody has to
give it Oh Google we have to start our
own technology cooperatives we have to
be able to take back our power or
they're just going to keep being more
powerful and more evil and they are
always going to make decisions with the
filter of profit which is always going
to lead to greater evil in the long run
even when there's a little bit of good
in it and we can create these things way
more powerfully than they can and they
will not be able to compete with us so
come join together Tech have actually
created the devices and these systems of
making our lives better thanks